{
  "content": {
    "title": "Implementation of Line Encoding Schemes",
    "section": "Post-Test",
    "questions": [
      {
        "id": "q1",
        "question": "Unipolar RZ is a type of ______ encoding.",
        "options": [
          "a. Line",
          "b. Block",
          "c. Scrambling",
          "d. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "a"
      },
      {
        "id": "q2",
        "question": "DC component is present in the encoded signal and there is loss of synchronization for long sequences of 0’s and 1’s in unipolar RZ.",
        "options": [
          "a. True",
          "b. False"
        ],
        "answer": "a"
      },
      {
        "id": "q3",
        "question": "NRZ-L is a type of _____ line encoding.",
        "options": [
          "a. Bipolar",
          "b. Multitransition",
          "c. Polar",
          "d. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "c"
      },
      {
        "id": "q4",
        "question": "Which of the following is not a Polar line encoding scheme?",
        "options": [
          "a. NRZ-I",
          "b. NRZ-L",
          "c. AMI",
          "d. All of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "c"
      },
      {
        "id": "q5",
        "question": "Manchester encoding is a combination of which two line encoding schemes.",
        "options": [
          "a. NRZ-L and RZ",
          "b. NRZ-I and RZ",
          "c. NRZ-L and AMI",
          "d. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "b"
      },
      {
        "id": "q6",
        "question": "The ________ represents the number of bits sent per second, whereas the ______ defines the number of signal elements per second in the signal.",
        "options": [
          "a. bit rate, baud rate",
          "b. baud rate , bit rate",
          "c. Both are same",
          "d. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "a"
      },
      {
        "id": "q7",
        "question": "In which line encoding scheme 0 bit is represented by Zero level and binary 1 is represented by alternating positive and negative voltages.",
        "options": [
          "a. NRZ-I",
          "b. AMI",
          "c. Pseudoternary",
          "d. All of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "b"
      },
      {
        "id": "q8",
        "question": "In Pseudoternary line encoding\nStatement 1: 0 bit is represented by Zero level.\nStatement 2: Binary 1 is represented by alternating positive and negative voltages.\nWhich of the above are true.",
        "options": [
          "a. Statement 1 is true and Statement 2 is false",
          "b. Statement 1 is false and Statement 2 is true",
          "c. Both are true",
          "d. Both are false"
        ],
        "answer": "d"
      },
      {
        "id": "q9",
        "question": "The polarities in NRZ format use?",
        "options": [
          "a. Complete pulse duration",
          "b. Half duration",
          "c. Both positive as well as negative value",
          "d. Each pulse is used for twice the duration"
        ],
        "answer": "a"
      },
      {
        "id": "q10",
        "question": "How many levels does manchester line encoding involve?",
        "options": [
          "a. Two levels with inversion in the middle of each bit",
          "b. Three levels with inversion in the middle of each bit",
          "c. Two levels without inversion in the middle of each bit",
          "d. Three levels without inversion in the middle of each bit"
        ],
        "answer": "a"
      }
    ]
  }
}
